Contact

tancinje@uhnj.org

www.linkedin.com/in/jennifer-t-gieger-bsn-rn-cen-tcrn-80b61588 (LinkedIn) etsy.com (Company) etsy.com (Company) instagram.com (Blog)

Top Skills

Emergency Room
Patient Advocacy
Emergency Nursing

Languages

English (Full Professional)
Sarcasm (Full Professional)

Certifications

CEN--Certified Emergency Nurse
ACLS--advanced cardiac life support
BLS--basic life support
PALS--pediatric advance life support
TCRN-Trauma Certified Registered
Nurse

Jennifer T. Gieger BSN RN CEN TCRN

Trauma Nurse at University Hospital, Newark NJ Greater New York City Area

Summary

Experienced Registered Nurse specializing in Emergency/Trauma Medicine for over 17 years. I am Certified Emergency Nurse and a Trauma Certified Registered Nurse, along with other certifications related to my field of expertise. At my current employer I am a trauma nurse, very dedicated and knowledgable person. Also I am team player, caring and fun to work with.

Newest member of the BCEN InstaCrew. Handle—glitterbomb ertraumanurse on Instagram.

I also just recently in December 2019 became a Mentor for the Emergency Nurses Association.

Owner and Creator of Glitter Bomb Bling. I opened this shop on Etsy. I am specializing in "blinging" out anything that will stay still. Currently I am crystallizing Badge/ID Holders, magnets and mini photo frames. I do not do customs and everything is unique and one of a kind. I am using top quality Swarovski and Precosia crystals and also strong E6000 adhesive. I am shipping all over the world. Check out my store on the link on this page. www.etsy.com/shop/glitterbombbling

Owner and Creator of Sparkle Nail Lacquer handmade/homemade glitter top coat nail polish. I have an exclusive shop on Etsy. I am a self taught nail polish creator. I used 5 free suspension glitter base with premium glitters, mica powders and color additives. All my polishes are made in small batches and i do have stock on hand ready to ship al over the world. I also sell top coats, base coats, cuticle oils and a new quick dry spray oil. I also do custom orders for all occasions. All polishes are made in my home and only by me.

Experience

University Hospital
Trauma Registered Nurse
September 2017 - Present (2 years 9 months)
Newark, New Jersey

University Teaching Hospital in Newark, NJ

519 Licensed Beds

Level 1 Trauma Department/Shock Trauma

Inner City Emergency Department—fast paced, high acuity.

Multiple treatment areas:

- -Trauma—Shock Trauma Room, 4 Trauma Bays
- -Adult—21 Bed Area, Asthma Chair Area
- -Pediatrics—10 Bed area, Asthma Chair Area
- -Psych/Crisis—8 Rooms
- -Fast Track—12 Rooms
- -Mid-Track—7 Bed Areas, ambulance triage, multi use area Multifaceted treatment teams. Very dedicated staff.

BOARD OF CERTIFICATION FOR EMERGENCY NURSING (BCEN®)

BCENInstacrew for the Board Certification for Emergency Nursing March 2020 - Present (3 months)

Posting on Instagram about BCEN, my own job, what it looks like to be a BCEN certified nurse, how you got started, test-taking tips, other nurses who inspire you, positive quotes for other nurses, your facility, etc...

Handle—glitterbomb_ertraumanurse on Instagram

Glitter Bomb Bling
Owner/Creator
August 2016 - Present (3 years 10 months)
Byram, New Jersey

Using high quality crystal rhinestones i.e. Swarovski and Preciosa stones and applying them to objects of desire or use.

I opened a store on Etsy so you can purchase items there. I do ship all over the world in a timely manner. I will not be making customs. I will only be making one of a kind pieces, No two will be alike.

Now making Swarovski Crystal Prism Suncatchers.

Making Blinged Out Badge Holders, Magnets, Glass Nail Files and Swarovski Crystal Prism Suncatchers.

www.etsy.com/shop/glitterbombbling

Sparkle Nail Lacquer Owner/Creator August 2012 - Present (7 years 10 months)

Byram, New Jersey

owner and creator of handmade nail polish. mostly glitter top coats.

i use nothing but the best in glitters and mica powders and a 5-Free base suspension.

Never tested on animals!

i make custom polishes for all occasions.

i also sell top and base coats, ridge filler, and large array of cuticle oils.

see my shop on etsy---i ship all over the world

www.etsy.com/shop/sparklenaillacquer

The Cardiovascular Care Group
Registered Nurse
September 2014 - November 2018 (4 years 3 months)
Clifton, NJ

- --Vascular Surgical Practice
- --Circulating Nurse in procedure room where vascular procedures are performed, cardiac monitoring patients, light sedation used.
- --Knowing of procedures and equipment i.e. fistulagrams, angioplasty, lower leg angiograms, stent placement, port a cath placement, permoath placement and removals.
- --Intake and discharge of patients.

Chilton Medical Center
Registered Nurse Emergency Department
September 2016 - September 2017 (1 year 1 month)
Pompton Plains, New Jersey

Working in a 20 bed adult main emergency department with an 8 bed fast track area and a pediatric emergency area also.

Hackensack University Medical Center
Emergency/Trauma Registered Nurse--Clinical Level III
May 2005 - September 2016 (11 years 5 months)
Hackensack, NJ

Registered Nurse in the Emergency/Trauma Department--Senior Staff--Clinical Level III

- --A 900 bed university hospital in Hackensack, NJ with a 75 bed Emergency Department with a full Trauma Services department.
- --This is a Magnet designated facility and the first one in New Jersey.
- --Constant learning environment and also has an emergency medicine program
- --High acuity and fast paced emergency department
- --Nursing autonomy and critical decision making
- --Using electronic charts and documentation
- --Expertise in taking care of the critically ill and traumatically ill.
- --Knowing all aspects of critical care and emergency medicine/nursing.
- --Patient population is young adult to geriatric.
- --Precepting new nurses to the department--teaching the ways of emergency nursing and ensuring hospital policy is being followed at all times.
- --Member of Trauma Council
- --Member of Throughput Committee. Co-chair
- --CEN, ACLS, TNCC, PALS, ENPC, BLS
- --winner of the MVP award by ER staff

Morristown Memorial Hospital Registered Nurse Emergency Department November 2009 - June 2013 (3 years 8 months) morristown, nj

emergency room nurse

St. Barnabas Hospital Registered Nurse Emergency Department October 2004 - April 2005 (7 months) emergency room nurse

Parkland Hospital

Registered Nurse Emergency Department August 2002 - September 2004 (2 years 2 months)

Dallas/Fort Worth Area

nurse internship program and emergency/trauma nursing

Doctors Hospital Registered Nurse Emergency Department May 2003 - August 2004 (1 year 4 months) emergency room nurse

Education

Bloomfield College

Bachelor's Degree, Registered Nursing/Registered Nurse · (1998 - 2002)

Berdan Institute

Medical Assisting, Medical/Clinical Assistant · (1994 - 1995)

Clifton High School

High School · (1990 - 1994)